<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Opensources on Docker Docs</title>
    <link>https://docs.docker.com/v1.10/opensource/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Opensources on Docker Docs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://docs.docker.com/v1.10/opensource/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced contributing</title>
      <link>https://docs.docker.com/v1.10/opensource/workflow/advanced-contributing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.docker.com/v1.10/opensource/workflow/advanced-contributing/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;advanced-contributing&#34;&gt;Advanced contributing&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this section, you learn about the more advanced contributions you can make.
They are advanced because they have a more involved workflow or require greater
programming experience. Don&amp;rsquo;t be scared off though, if you like to stretch and
challenge yourself, this is the place for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This section gives generalized instructions for advanced contributions. You&amp;rsquo;ll
read about the workflow but there are not specific descriptions of commands.
Your goal should be to understand the processes described.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, you should have read and worked through the earlier parts of
the project contributor guide. You should also have
&lt;a href=&#34;../make-a-contribution/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; made at least one project contribution&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;refactor-or-cleanup-proposal&#34;&gt;Refactor or cleanup proposal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A refactor or cleanup proposal changes Docker&amp;rsquo;s internal structure without
altering the external behavior. To make this type of proposal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fork &lt;code&gt;docker/docker&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make your changes in a feature branch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sync and rebase with &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; as you work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Run the full test suite.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Submit your code through a pull request (PR).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PR&amp;rsquo;s title should have the format:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cleanup:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;short title&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your changes required logic changes, note that in your request.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Work through Docker&amp;rsquo;s review process until merge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;design-proposal&#34;&gt;Design proposal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A design proposal solves a problem or adds a feature to the Docker software.
The process for submitting design proposals requires two pull requests, one
for the design and one for the implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../opensource/workflow/images/proposal.png&#34; alt=&#34;Simple process&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important thing to notice is that both the design pull request and the
implementation pull request go through a review. In other words, there is
considerable time commitment in a design proposal; so, you might want to pair
with someone on design work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following provides greater detail on the process:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Come up with an idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideas usually come from limitations users feel working with a product. So,
take some time to really use Docker. Try it on different platforms; explore
how it works with different web applications. Go to some community events
and find out what other users want.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Review existing issues and proposals to make sure no other user is proposing a similar idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The design proposals are &lt;a
href=&#34;https://github.com/docker/docker/pulls?q=is%3Aopen+is%3Apr+label%
3Akind%2Fproposal&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;all online in our GitHub pull requests&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Talk to the community about your idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have lots of &lt;a href=&#34;../../get-help/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;community forums&lt;/a&gt;
where you can get feedback on your idea. Float your idea in a forum or two
to get some commentary going on it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fork &lt;code&gt;docker/docker&lt;/code&gt; and clone the repo to your local host.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create a new Markdown file in the area you wish to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if you want to redesign our daemon create a new file under the
&lt;code&gt;daemon/&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Name the file descriptively, for example &lt;code&gt;redesign-daemon-proposal.md&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Write a proposal for your change into the file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a Markdown file that describes your idea. Your proposal
should include information like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why is this change needed or what are the use cases?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the requirements this change should meet?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are some ways to design/implement this feature?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which design/implementation do you think is best and why?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the risks or limitations of your proposal?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is your chance to convince people your idea is sound.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Submit your proposal in a pull request to &lt;code&gt;docker/docker&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The title should have the format:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proposal:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;short title&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The body of the pull request should include a brief summary of your change
and then say something like &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;See the file for a complete description&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Refine your proposal through review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The maintainers and the community review your proposal. You&amp;rsquo;ll need to
answer questions and sometimes explain or defend your approach. This is
chance for everyone to both teach and learn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pull request accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your request may also be rejected. Not every idea is a good fit for Docker.
Let&amp;rsquo;s assume though your proposal succeeded.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Implement your idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Implementation uses all the standard practices of any contribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fork &lt;code&gt;docker/docker&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create a feature branch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sync frequently back to master&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;test as you go and full test before a PR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you run into issues, the community is there to help.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you have a complete implementation, submit a pull request back to &lt;code&gt;docker/docker&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Review and iterate on your code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are making a large code change, you can expect greater scrutiny
during this phase.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Acceptance and merge!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-the-advanced-process&#34;&gt;About the advanced process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Docker is a large project. Our core team gets a great many design proposals.
Design proposal discussions can span days, weeks, and longer. The number of comments can reach the 100s.
In that situation, following the discussion flow and the decisions reached is crucial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making a pull request with a design proposal simplifies this process:
* you can leave comments on specific design proposal line
* replies around line are easy to track
* as a proposal changes and is updated, pages reset as line items resolve
* GitHub maintains the entire history&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While proposals in pull requests do not end up merged into a master repository, they provide a convenient tool for managing the design process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Board member profiles</title>
      <link>https://docs.docker.com/v1.10/opensource/governance/board-profiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.docker.com/v1.10/opensource/governance/board-profiles/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;project-leadership&#34;&gt;Project Leadership&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Docker Project is led by three individuals who are responsible for the direction, operations, quality and community of the project as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;chief-architect-solomon-hykes&#34;&gt;Chief Architect : Solomon Hykes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chief architect is responsible for the general direction of the project,
defining it’s design principles, and preserving the integrity of it’s overall
architecture as the platform grows and matures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;chief-maintainer-michael-crosby&#34;&gt;Chief Maintainer : Michael Crosby&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chief maintainer is responsible for all aspects of quality for the project
including code reviews, usability, stability, security and performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;chief-operator-steve-francia&#34;&gt;Chief Operator : Steve Francia&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chief operator is responsible for the day-to-day operations of the project
including: facilitating communications amongst all the contributors; tracking
release schedules; managing the relationship with downstream distributions and
upstream dependencies; and helping new contributors to get involved and become
successful contributors and maintainers. The role is also responsible for
managing and measuring the success of the overall project and ensuring it is
governed properly working in concert with the Docker Governance Advisory Board
(DGAB).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;members-of-the-2015-dgab&#34;&gt;Members of the 2015 DGAB&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DGAB is made up of 16 individual who represent the ecosystem, contributors
and community of the Docker Project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;docker&#34;&gt;Docker&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Michael Crosby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steve Francia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stephen Day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arnaud Poterie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;individual-contributors&#34;&gt;Individual Contributors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andrew Tianon Page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aleksa Sarai&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Harald Albers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Darren Shepherd&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;corporate-contributors&#34;&gt;Corporate Contributors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jeff Borek (IBM)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dan Walsh (RedHat)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ahmet Alp Balkan (Microsoft)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rohit Jnagal (Google)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;user&#34;&gt;User&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nicola Paolucci (Atlassian)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Burke Libbey (Shopify)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meghdoot Bhattacharya (PayPal)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tapabrata Pal (Capital One)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code of conduct</title>
      <link>https://docs.docker.com/v1.10/opensource/governance/conduct-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.docker.com/v1.10/opensource/governance/conduct-code/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;code-of-conduct&#34;&gt;Code of conduct&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Docker project has not currently adopted a Code of Conduct though there is
work being done in this regard. Without a formal Code of Conduct being adopted
by the project, it is anticipated that participants and contributors follow the
generic &lt;a href=&#34;http://contributor-covenant.org&#34;&gt;contributor covenant&lt;/a&gt; until a formal
code of conduct is adopted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;contributor-covenant&#34;&gt;Contributor Covenant&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As contributors and maintainers of this project, we pledge to respect all people
who contribute through reporting issues, posting feature requests, updating
documentation, submitting pull requests or patches, and other activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are committed to making participation in this project a harassment-free
experience for everyone, regardless of level of experience, gender, gender
identity and expression, sexual orientation, disability, personal appearance,
body size, race, ethnicity, age, or religion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples of unacceptable behavior by participants include the use of sexual
language or imagery, derogatory comments or personal attacks, trolling, public
or private harassment, insults, or other unprofessional conduct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project maintainers have the right and responsibility to remove, edit, or
reject comments, commits, code, wiki edits, issues, and other contributions
that are not aligned to this Code of Conduct. Project maintainers who do not
follow the Code of Conduct may be removed from the project team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instances of abusive, harassing, or otherwise unacceptable behavior may be
reported by opening an issue or contacting one or more of the project
maintainers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Code of Conduct is adapted from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://contributor-covenant.org&#34;&gt;Contributor
Covenant&lt;/a&gt;, version 1.0.0, available at
&lt;a href=&#34;http://contributor-covenant.org/version/1/0/0/&#34;&gt;http://contributor-covenant.org/version/1/0/0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding style checklist</title>
      <link>https://docs.docker.com/v1.10/opensource/workflow/coding-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.docker.com/v1.10/opensource/workflow/coding-style/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;coding-style-checklist&#34;&gt;Coding style checklist&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This checklist summarizes the material you experienced working through &lt;a href=&#34;../v1.10/opensource/workflow/make-a-contribution/&#34;&gt;make a
code contribution&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;../v1.10/opensource/workflow/advanced-contributing/&#34;&gt;advanced
contributing&lt;/a&gt;. The checklist applies to both
program code and documentation code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;change-and-commit-code&#34;&gt;Change and commit code&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fork the &lt;code&gt;docker/docker&lt;/code&gt; repository.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make changes on your fork in a feature branch. Name your branch &lt;code&gt;XXXX-something&lt;/code&gt;
where &lt;code&gt;XXXX&lt;/code&gt; is the issue number you are working on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;gofmt -s -w file.go&lt;/code&gt; on each changed file before
committing your changes. Most editors have plug-ins that do this automatically.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;golint&lt;/code&gt; on each changed file before
committing your changes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Update the documentation when creating or modifying features.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Commits that fix or close an issue should reference them in the commit message
&lt;code&gt;Closes #XXXX&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Fixes #XXXX&lt;/code&gt;. Mentions help by automatically closing the
issue on a merge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After every commit, run the test suite and ensure it is passing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sync and rebase frequently as you code to keep up with &lt;code&gt;docker&lt;/code&gt; master.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Set your &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; signature and make sure you sign each commit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do not add yourself to the &lt;code&gt;AUTHORS&lt;/code&gt; file. This file is autogenerated from the
Git history.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tests-and-testing&#34;&gt;Tests and testing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Submit unit tests for your changes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make use of the builtin Go test framework built.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use existing Docker test files (&lt;code&gt;name_test.go&lt;/code&gt;) for inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Run &lt;a href=&#34;../../project/test-and-docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the full test suite&lt;/a&gt; on your
branch before submitting a pull request.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;make docs&lt;/code&gt; to build the documentation and then check it locally.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hemingwayapp.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;online grammar
checker&lt;/a&gt; or similar to test you documentation changes for clarity,
concision, and correctness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;pull-requests&#34;&gt;Pull requests&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sync and cleanly rebase on top of Docker&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; without multiple branches
mixed into the PR.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before the pull request, squash your commits into logical units of work using
&lt;code&gt;git rebase -i&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;git push -f&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Include documentation changes in the same commit so that a revert would
remove all traces of the feature or fix.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reference each issue in your pull request description (&lt;code&gt;#XXXX&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;respond-to-pull-requests-reviews&#34;&gt;Respond to pull requests reviews&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Docker maintainers use LGTM (&lt;strong&gt;l&lt;/strong&gt;ooks-&lt;strong&gt;g&lt;/strong&gt;ood-&lt;strong&gt;t&lt;/strong&gt;o-&lt;strong&gt;m&lt;/strong&gt;e) in PR comments
to indicate acceptance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Code review comments may be added to your pull request. Discuss, then make
the suggested modifications and push additional commits to your feature
branch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Incorporate changes on your feature branch and push to your fork. This
automatically updates your open pull request.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Post a comment after pushing to alert reviewers to PR changes; pushing a
change does not send notifications.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A change requires LGTMs from an absolute majority maintainers of an
affected component. For example, if you change &lt;code&gt;docs/&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;registry/&lt;/code&gt; code,
an absolute majority of the &lt;code&gt;docs/&lt;/code&gt; and the &lt;code&gt;registry/&lt;/code&gt; maintainers must
approve your PR.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;merges-after-pull-requests&#34;&gt;Merges after pull requests&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a merge, &lt;a href=&#34;https://master.dockerproject.org/&#34;&gt;a master build&lt;/a&gt; is
available almost immediately.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you made a documentation change, you can see it at
&lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.master.dockerproject.org/&#34;&gt;docs.master.dockerproject.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure Git for contributing</title>
      <link>https://docs.docker.com/v1.10/opensource/project/set-up-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.docker.com/v1.10/opensource/project/set-up-git/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;configure-git-for-contributing&#34;&gt;Configure Git for contributing&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work through this page to configure Git and a repository you&amp;rsquo;ll use throughout
the Contributor Guide. The work you do further in the guide, depends on the work
you do here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fork-and-clone-the-docker-code&#34;&gt;Fork and clone the Docker code&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before contributing, you first fork the Docker code repository. A fork copies
a repository at a particular point in time. GitHub tracks for you where a fork
originates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you make contributions, you change your fork&amp;rsquo;s code. When you are ready,
you make a pull request back to the original Docker repository. If you aren&amp;rsquo;t
familiar with this workflow, don&amp;rsquo;t worry, this guide walks you through all the
steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To fork and clone Docker:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open a browser and log into GitHub with your account.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Go to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/docker/docker&#34;
target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;docker/docker repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Click the &amp;ldquo;Fork&amp;rdquo; button in the upper right corner of the GitHub interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../opensource/project/images/fork_docker.png&#34; alt=&#34;Branch Signature&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GitHub forks the repository to your GitHub account. The original
&lt;code&gt;docker/docker&lt;/code&gt; repository becomes a new fork &lt;code&gt;YOUR_ACCOUNT/docker&lt;/code&gt; under
your account.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Copy your fork&amp;rsquo;s clone URL from GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GitHub allows you to use HTTPS or SSH protocols for clones. You can use the
&lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; command line or clients like Subversion to clone a repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../opensource/project/images/copy_url.png&#34; alt=&#34;Copy clone URL&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This guide assume you are using the HTTPS protocol and the &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; command
line. If you are comfortable with SSH and some other tool, feel free to use
that instead. You&amp;rsquo;ll need to convert what you see in the guide to what is
appropriate to your tool.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open a terminal window on your local host and change to your home directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cd ~
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Windows, you&amp;rsquo;ll work in your Docker Quickstart Terminal window instead of
Powershell or a &lt;code&gt;cmd&lt;/code&gt; window.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create a &lt;code&gt;repos&lt;/code&gt; directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ mkdir repos
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Change into your &lt;code&gt;repos&lt;/code&gt; directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cd repos
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clone the fork to your local host into a repository called &lt;code&gt;docker-fork&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git clone https://github.com/moxiegirl/docker.git docker-fork
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naming your local repo &lt;code&gt;docker-fork&lt;/code&gt; should help make these instructions
easier to follow; experienced coders don&amp;rsquo;t typically change the name.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Change directory into your new &lt;code&gt;docker-fork&lt;/code&gt; directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cd docker-fork
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a moment to familiarize yourself with the repository&amp;rsquo;s contents. List
the contents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;set-your-signature-and-an-upstream-remote&#34;&gt;Set your signature and an upstream remote&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you contribute to Docker, you must certify you agree with the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://developercertificate.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Developer Certificate of Origin&lt;/a&gt;.
You indicate your agreement by signing your &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; commits like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Signed-off-by: Pat Smith &amp;lt;pat.smith@email.com&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create a signature, you configure your username and email address in Git.
You can set these globally or locally on just your &lt;code&gt;docker-fork&lt;/code&gt; repository.
You must sign with your real name. You can sign your git commit automatically
with &lt;code&gt;git commit -s&lt;/code&gt;. Docker does not accept anonymous contributions or contributions
through pseudonyms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you change code in your fork, you&amp;rsquo;ll want to keep it in sync with the changes
others make in the &lt;code&gt;docker/docker&lt;/code&gt; repository. To make syncing easier, you&amp;rsquo;ll
also add a &lt;em&gt;remote&lt;/em&gt; called &lt;code&gt;upstream&lt;/code&gt; that points to &lt;code&gt;docker/docker&lt;/code&gt;. A remote
is just another project version hosted on the internet or network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To configure your username, email, and add a remote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Change to the root of your &lt;code&gt;docker-fork&lt;/code&gt; repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cd docker-fork
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Set your &lt;code&gt;user.name&lt;/code&gt; for the repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git config --local user.name &amp;quot;FirstName LastName&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Set your &lt;code&gt;user.email&lt;/code&gt; for the repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git config --local user.email &amp;quot;emailname@mycompany.com&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Set your local repo to track changes upstream, on the &lt;code&gt;docker&lt;/code&gt; repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git remote add upstream https://github.com/docker/docker.git
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Check the result in your &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; configuration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git config --local -l
core.repositoryformatversion=0
core.filemode=true
core.bare=false
core.logallrefupdates=true
remote.origin.url=https://github.com/moxiegirl/docker.git
remote.origin.fetch=+refs/heads/*:refs/remotes/origin/*
branch.master.remote=origin
branch.master.merge=refs/heads/master
user.name=Mary Anthony
user.email=mary@docker.com
remote.upstream.url=https://github.com/docker/docker.git
remote.upstream.fetch=+refs/heads/*:refs/remotes/upstream/*
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To list just the remotes use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git remote -v
origin  https://github.com/moxiegirl/docker.git (fetch)
origin  https://github.com/moxiegirl/docker.git (push)
upstream    https://github.com/docker/docker.git (fetch)
upstream    https://github.com/docker/docker.git (push)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;create-and-push-a-branch&#34;&gt;Create and push a branch&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you change code in your fork, make your changes on a repository branch.
The branch name should reflect what you are working on. In this section, you
create a branch, make a change, and push it up to your fork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This branch is just for testing your config for this guide. The changes are part
of a dry run, so the branch name will be dry-run-test. To create and push
the branch to your fork on GitHub:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open a terminal and go to the root of your &lt;code&gt;docker-fork&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cd docker-fork
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create a &lt;code&gt;dry-run-test&lt;/code&gt; branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git checkout -b dry-run-test
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This command creates the branch and switches the repository to it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Verify you are in your new branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git branch
* dry-run-test
  master
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current branch has an * (asterisk) marker. So, these results shows you
are on the right branch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create a &lt;code&gt;TEST.md&lt;/code&gt; file in the repository&amp;rsquo;s root.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ touch TEST.md
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edit the file and add your email and location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../opensource/project/images/contributor-edit.png&#34; alt=&#34;Add your information&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use any text editor you are comfortable with.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Save and close the file.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Check the status of your branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git status
On branch dry-run-test
Untracked files:
  (use &amp;quot;git add &amp;lt;file&amp;gt;...&amp;quot; to include in what will be committed)

    TEST.md

nothing added to commit but untracked files present (use &amp;quot;git add&amp;quot; to track)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve only changed the one file. It is untracked so far by git.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add your file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git add TEST.md
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is the only &lt;em&gt;staged&lt;/em&gt; file. Stage is fancy word for work that Git is
tracking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sign and commit your change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git commit -s -m &amp;quot;Making a dry run test.&amp;quot;
[dry-run-test 6e728fb] Making a dry run test
 1 file changed, 1 insertion(+)
 create mode 100644 TEST.md
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commit messages should have a short summary sentence of no more than 50
characters. Optionally, you can also include a more detailed explanation
after the summary. Separate the summary from any explanation with an empty
line.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Push your changes to GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git push --set-upstream origin dry-run-test
Username for &#39;https://github.com&#39;: moxiegirl
Password for &#39;https://moxiegirl@github.com&#39;:
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Git prompts you for your GitHub username and password. Then, the command
returns a result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Counting objects: 13, done.
Compressing objects: 100% (2/2), done.
Writing objects: 100% (3/3), 320 bytes | 0 bytes/s, done.
Total 3 (delta 1), reused 0 (delta 0)
To https://github.com/moxiegirl/docker.git
 * [new branch]      dry-run-test -&amp;gt; dry-run-test
Branch dry-run-test set up to track remote branch dry-run-test from origin.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open your browser to GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Navigate to your Docker fork.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make sure the &lt;code&gt;dry-run-test&lt;/code&gt; branch exists, that it has your commit, and the
commit is signed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../opensource/project/images/branch-sig.png&#34; alt=&#34;Branch Signature&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;where-to-go-next&#34;&gt;Where to go next&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulations, you have finished configuring both your local host environment
and Git for contributing. In the next section you&amp;rsquo;ll &lt;a href=&#34;../v1.10/opensource/project/set-up-dev-env/&#34;&gt;learn how to set up and
work in a Docker development container&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contribute to Kitematic</title>
      <link>https://docs.docker.com/v1.10/opensource/kitematic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.docker.com/v1.10/opensource/kitematic/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;contribute-to-kitematic&#34;&gt;Contribute to Kitematic&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../v1.10/opensource/kitematic/get_started/&#34;&gt;Get started&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../v1.10/opensource/kitematic/find_issue/&#34;&gt;Find an issue on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../v1.10/opensource/kitematic/set_up_dev/&#34;&gt;Set up for Kitematic development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../v1.10/opensource/kitematic/work_issue/&#34;&gt;Develop in Kitematic (work on an issue)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../v1.10/opensource/kitematic/create_pr/&#34;&gt;Review your branch and create a pull request (PR)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../v1.10/opensource/kitematic/next_steps/&#34;&gt;Where to learn more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contribution workflow</title>
      <link>https://docs.docker.com/v1.10/opensource/workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.docker.com/v1.10/opensource/workflow/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;contribution-workflow&#34;&gt;Contribution workflow&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../v1.10/opensource/workflow/make-a-contribution/&#34;&gt;Understand how to contribute&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../v1.10/opensource/workflow/find-an-issue/&#34;&gt;Find and claim an issue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../v1.10/opensource/workflow/work-issue/&#34;&gt;Work on your issue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../v1.10/opensource/workflow/create-pr/&#34;&gt;Create a pull request&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../v1.10/opensource/workflow/review-pr/&#34;&gt;Participate in the PR review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../v1.10/opensource/workflow/advanced-contributing/&#34;&gt;Advanced contributing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../v1.10/opensource/workflow/coding-style/&#34;&gt;Coding style checklist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a pull request (PR)</title>
      <link>https://docs.docker.com/v1.10/opensource/kitematic/create_pr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.docker.com/v1.10/opensource/kitematic/create_pr/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;create-a-pull-request-pr&#34;&gt;Create a pull request (PR)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you follow the &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.docker.com/opensource/workflow/create-pr/#rebase-your-branch&#34;
target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; rebase guidelines &lt;/a&gt; before you make a pull request.
Rebasing helps verify that your commit is clean, and allows for an easier and faster merge of your code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve cleaned up your commits:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Push your code to your repository under the same name as your local branch (in the case of this example, 1191-branch).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git push origin 1191-branch:1191-branch
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open a web browser to your fork on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should see the latest activity from your branch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;Compare &amp;amp; pull request&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system displays the pull request dialog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../opensource/kitematic/images/pr_compare.png&#34; alt=&#34;Pull Request dialog&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pull request compares your changes to the &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch on the
&lt;code&gt;kitematic/kitematic&lt;/code&gt; repository.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edit the pull request description and add a reference to the issue you are fixing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GitHub helps you out by searching for the issue as you type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../opensource/kitematic/images/pr_describe_issue.png&#34; alt=&#34;Fixes issue&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scroll down and verify the PR contains the commits and changes you expect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, is the file count correct? Are the changes in the files what
you expect?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../opensource/kitematic/images/pr_commits_expected.png&#34; alt=&#34;Commits&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;Create pull request&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system creates the request and opens it for you in the &lt;code&gt;kitematic/kitematic&lt;/code&gt;
repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../opensource/kitematic/images/pr_pull_request_made.png&#34; alt=&#34;Pull request made&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;where-to-go-next&#34;&gt;Where to go next&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulations! You&amp;rsquo;ve created your first pull request to Kitematic!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step in this process is to participate your PR&amp;rsquo;s review. To learn more, and try another development exercise, see &lt;a href=&#34;../v1.10/opensource/kitematic/next_steps/&#34;&gt;where to learn more&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- The next step in the process for this PR is learn how to &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.docker.com/project/review-pr/&#34;
target=_blank&#34;&gt;participate in your PR&#39;s
review &lt;/a&gt;. --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a pull request (PR)</title>
      <link>https://docs.docker.com/v1.10/opensource/workflow/create-pr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.docker.com/v1.10/opensource/workflow/create-pr/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;create-a-pull-request-pr&#34;&gt;Create a pull request (PR)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A pull request (PR) sends your changes to the Docker maintainers for review. You
create a pull request on GitHub. A pull request &amp;ldquo;pulls&amp;rdquo; changes from your forked
repository into the &lt;code&gt;docker/docker&lt;/code&gt; repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/docker/docker/pulls&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the
list of active pull requests to Docker&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;check-your-work&#34;&gt;Check your work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you create a pull request, check your work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a terminal window, go to the root of your &lt;code&gt;docker-fork&lt;/code&gt; repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cd ~/repos/docker-fork
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Checkout your feature branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git checkout 11038-fix-rhel-link
Switched to branch &#39;11038-fix-rhel-link&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Run the full test suite on your branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ make test
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the tests should pass. If they don&amp;rsquo;t, find out why and correct the
situation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Optionally, if modified the documentation, build the documentation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ make docs
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Commit and push any changes that result from your checks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;rebase-your-branch&#34;&gt;Rebase your branch&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always rebase and squash your commits before making a pull request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Checkout your feature branch in your local &lt;code&gt;docker-fork&lt;/code&gt; repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the branch associated with your request.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fetch any last minute changes from &lt;code&gt;docker/docker&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git fetch upstream master
From github.com:docker/docker
 * branch            master     -&amp;gt; FETCH_HEAD
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Start an interactive rebase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git rebase -i upstream/master
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rebase opens an editor with a list of commits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;pick 1a79f55 Tweak some of the other text for grammar
pick 53e4983 Fix a link
pick 3ce07bb Add a new line about RHEL
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Replace the &lt;code&gt;pick&lt;/code&gt; keyword with &lt;code&gt;squash&lt;/code&gt; on all but the first commit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;pick 1a79f55 Tweak some of the other text for grammar
squash 53e4983 Fix a link
squash 3ce07bb Add a new line about RHEL
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you save the changes and quit from the editor, git starts
the rebase, reporting the progress along the way. Sometimes
your changes can conflict with the work of others. If git
encounters a conflict, it stops the rebase, and prints guidance
for how to correct the conflict.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edit and save your commit message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git commit -s
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure your message includes &lt;a href=&#34;../opensource/project/set-up-git/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;your signature&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Force push any changes to your fork on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git push -f origin 11038-fix-rhel-link
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;create-a-pr-on-github&#34;&gt;Create a PR on GitHub&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You create and manage PRs on GitHub:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open your browser to your fork on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should see the latest activity from your branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../opensource/workflow/images/latest_commits.png&#34; alt=&#34;Latest commits&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Click &amp;ldquo;Compare &amp;amp; pull request.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system displays the pull request dialog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../opensource/workflow/images/to_from_pr.png&#34; alt=&#34;PR dialog&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pull request compares your changes to the &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch on the
&lt;code&gt;docker/docker&lt;/code&gt; repository.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edit the dialog&amp;rsquo;s description and add a reference to the issue you are fixing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GitHub helps you out by searching for the issue as you type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../opensource/workflow/images/fixes_num.png&#34; alt=&#34;Fixes issue&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scroll down and verify the PR contains the commits and changes you expect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, is the file count correct? Are the changes in the files what
you expect?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../opensource/workflow/images/commits_expected.png&#34; alt=&#34;Commits&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Press &amp;ldquo;Create pull request&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system creates the request and opens it for you in the &lt;code&gt;docker/docker&lt;/code&gt;
repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../opensource/workflow/images/pull_request_made.png&#34; alt=&#34;Pull request made&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;where-to-go-next&#34;&gt;Where to go next&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulations, you&amp;rsquo;ve created your first pull request to Docker. The next
step is for you learn how to &lt;a href=&#34;../v1.10/opensource/workflow/review-pr/&#34;&gt;participate in your PR&amp;rsquo;s
review&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Develop in Kitematic (work on an issue)</title>
      <link>https://docs.docker.com/v1.10/opensource/kitematic/work_issue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.docker.com/v1.10/opensource/kitematic/work_issue/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;develop-in-kitematic-work-on-an-issue&#34;&gt;Develop in Kitematic (work on an issue)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this tutorial, we will work on issue &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/docker/kitematic/issues/1191&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; #1191&lt;/a&gt; which is a request to display the container id in Kitematic for easy identification. (Currently, Kitematic shows the container name but not the id.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do this, edit the container &lt;code&gt;General Settings&lt;/code&gt; layout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open the project in your favorite editor - We recommend using &lt;a href=&#34;https://atom.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; Atom&lt;/a&gt; as it&amp;rsquo;s a full featured editor with great &lt;a href=&#34;http://eslint.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; ES lint&lt;/a&gt; support to keep your code organized.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open the &lt;code&gt;ContainerSettingsGeneral.react.js&lt;/code&gt; file which is found under the &lt;code&gt;src/components/&lt;/code&gt; folder and look for the following piece of code, which is in fact the layout (like HTML in the browser):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    return (
        &amp;lt;div className=&amp;quot;settings-panel&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
        ...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(line ~200)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Above this code we will create a javascript variable that will allow us to display  our container id:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;let shortId = (
    &amp;lt;div className=&amp;quot;settings-section&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Container Id&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;div className=&amp;quot;container-name&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;input id=&amp;quot;input-container-name&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;text&amp;quot; className=&amp;quot;line&amp;quot; placeholder=&amp;quot;Container Id&amp;quot; defaultValue={this.props.container.Id.substr(0, 12)} readOnly&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/input&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This snippet has been saved as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/FrenchBen/0f514e7b3c584e8d46b5&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub gist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;We then need to add the variable to the rendered view, by adding it below the &lt;code&gt;{rename}&lt;/code&gt; tag. The new render code should look something like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;      return (
           &amp;lt;div className=&amp;quot;settings-panel&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
                {rename}
                {shortId}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, the updated code should look similar to this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../opensource/kitematic/images/settings-code-example.png&#34; alt=&#34;Javascript to display container id in kitematic&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Save the code changes, re-start Kitematic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ npm start
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, the container ID should show on the General Settings tab, along with the container name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../opensource/kitematic/images/kitematic_gui_container_id.png&#34; alt=&#34;Container ID&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note that the container ID in Kitematic matches the ID shown as output to the &lt;code&gt;docker ps&lt;/code&gt; command.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can close the Kitematic application now, and kill the running process in the terminal via CTRL+c.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stage your changes by adding them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git add src/components/ContainerSettingsGeneral.react.js
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Commit your code changes with a comment that explains what this fixes or closes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git commit -s -m &amp;quot;added container ID to show on settings tab, fixes issue #1191&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(See &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/docker/docker/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.md#coding-style&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Coding Style&lt;/a&gt; in the general guidelines on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/docker/docker/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Contributing to Docker&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;where-to-go-next&#34;&gt;Where to go next&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, you are ready to &lt;a href=&#34;../v1.10/opensource/kitematic/create_pr/&#34;&gt;Review your branch and create a pull request&lt;/a&gt; to merge your new feature into Kitematic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Governance Advisory Board</title>
      <link>https://docs.docker.com/v1.10/opensource/governance/dgab-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.docker.com/v1.10/opensource/governance/dgab-info/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;docker-governance-advisory-board-june-2015-version&#34;&gt;Docker Governance Advisory Board: June 2015 Version&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An initial version of this proposal was posted for comments on April 30th,
2014. This version reflects all comments received prior to announcing the
initial members/nominees for the board on June 10th. This document was
updated to reflect the new membership for 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-0-background&#34;&gt;1.0 Background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Docker project is experiencing incredible momentum in project growth,
adoption, and contribution. As of June 9, 2014, there are over 460
contributors, 95% of whom do not work for the project’s commercial sponsor.
Large numbers of projects are being built on top of or incorporating Docker
(over 7,000 projects with “Docker” in the title on GitHub), and there is a
large and growing community of users. The project was designed from the outset
to have a very open structure, including open design, open contribution, and
consistent use of tools across the project. Maintainers include both Docker,
Inc. and non-Docker Inc. employees. Given the large numbers of contributors,
users, and companies with a stake in the future of the project, the project
leadership is looking to supplement the current governance and contribution
mechanisms with an advisory board, as part of its long term commitment to open
governance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-0-purpose&#34;&gt;2.0 Purpose&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The primary purpose of the Docker Governance Advisory Board (DGAB) is to advise
the Docker project leadership (Leadership) on matters related to supporting the
long term governance, structure, and roadmap of the Docker project. The
following main areas are included in this charter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide a forum for individuals, users, and companies to discuss the issues
under the DGAB purview (SCOPE)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide guidance and input to Leadership, and where possible, present a
consistent and consolidated opinion from the broader Docker community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Produce a formal, twice yearly report to the Leadership and broader Docker
community of the status of and progress made in all areas under the purview
of the DGAB.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Promote and support the use of Docker in manner consistent with Guiding *&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;principles-of-the-project-and-the-core-criteria&#34;&gt;Principles of the project and the Core Criteria&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DGAB is not:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intended to serve as a governance board. The DGAB advises, but does not manage, the Docker project leadership&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intended to replace existing mechanisms for community input, governance, or contribution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intended to assume a formal, fiduciary role with respect to the project. The DGAB membership will not be asked to provide funds to the project, assume liabilities with respect to the project or their activities, or assume responsibility for enforcing either trademarks or DGAB recommendations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-0-scope&#34;&gt;3.0 Scope&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DGAB is expected to provide input and formal recommendations regarding the following areas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker project long term roadmap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker project policies and procedures around maintenance and contributions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker project policies and procedures around intellectual property, trademark, and licensing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Core Criteria for Docker-related project (c.f. section 7.0)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker project long term governance model&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-0-meetings-and-memberships&#34;&gt;4.0 Meetings and Memberships&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-1-general&#34;&gt;4.1 General&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DGAB will have 16 members&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Docker Chief Maintainer: Michael Crosby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Docker Chief Operator: Steve Francia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 seats for the top core maintainers (Docker)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Up to 12 additional seats: 4 corporate seats, 4 individual or small business seats, 4 “user” seats&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;No fee or sponsorship is required for membership&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The membership term will last 12 months. With the exception of the Chief Maintainer, all members can serve a maximum of two consecutive terms&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The selection process is intended to be open, transparent, and guided by objective criteria for membership.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The DGAB shall elect a Chair and Vice Chair from amongst their members to serve a renewable 6 month term.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Chair or Vice-Chair shall prepare an agenda for and preside over regular meetings of the DGAB. These meetings shall occur as frequently as the DGAB determines is in the project’s best interest, but no less than quarterly&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Docker, inc. shall appoint a temporary chair to set the agenda for the first meeting and preside until the election shall occur.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A member of the DGAB may be removed by a resolution of the DGAB supported by more than two thirds of its membership.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The DGAB may fill any vacancy arising by removal or resignation by a simple majority vote to fill the remainder of the term of the vacating member.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The rules of election and membership outlined in this section may be varied by a resolution of the DGAB supported by more than two thirds of its voting membership.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;All project maintainers are welcome as participants and observers at DGAB meetings&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-2-selection-process&#34;&gt;4.2 Selection Process&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;contributors&#34;&gt;Contributors:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four seats will be granted to the top contributors, as measured
by non-trivial pull requests merged to master in the last 6 months. Trivial
pull requests are typos, minor document corrections, or other items that do not
require a DCO. These seats will be reserved for individual contributors who are
neither employees of Docker, Inc. nor employees of companies that hold a
corporate seat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;corporate-seats&#34;&gt;Corporate seats:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nomination is restricted to companies for whom all three of
the following are true&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are in the top 8 companies in terms of non-trivial pull requests merged to
master in the past six months as measured by contributions by all employees&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have employees as maintainers and/or make significant contributions to the
code base&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have committed to integrate Docker into widely used products in a manner
consistent with Core Criteria. (c.f. section 7.0)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once nomination has been closed, selection of corporate seats will be made by a
vote by eligible contributors. Eligible contributors are those who have had at
least one non-trivial pull request merged to master in the past six months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;user-seats&#34;&gt;User seats:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These seats are for organizations that are using Docker. To be nominated, an
organization must be using Docker in production and have published a use case.
Once nomination has been closed, selection will be made by a vote by eligible
contributors. Eligible contributors are those who have had at least one
non-trivial pull request merged to master in the past six months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-0-operation&#34;&gt;5.0 Operation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DGAB is authorized to seek advice and counsel from other interested parties
and invited experts as appropriate&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any outside party wishing to bring an issue before the DGAB may do so by
emailing the DGAB mailing list&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DGAB shall provide transparent and timely reporting (through any mechanism
it deems appropriate) to the Community at large on all of its activities,
subject to the right of any individual to designate their comments and the
ensuing discussion as &amp;ldquo;in confidence,&amp;rdquo; in which case the public report shall
contain only a note of the request and an agreed summary (if any) of the
substance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DGAB is being formed at the discretion of the Leadership. The Leadership
alone may decide to terminate the DGAB in its sole discretion; provided
however, that the Leadership shall first consult the DGAB Chair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DGAB and its members shall abide by appropriate antitrust guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;6-0-open-governance-principles&#34;&gt;6.0 Open Governance Principles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DGAB will formulate recommendations in conjunction with the following, open governance principles&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;open-participation&#34;&gt;Open participation:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the project, anyone should be able to participate and contribute.
All bugs and tasks will be tracked in a public tracker and all of the source
code and all of the tools needed to build it will be available under an open
license permitting unrestricted use&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;open-technical-meritocracy&#34;&gt;Open technical meritocracy:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technical merit over pride of authorship. Code
is contributed for the express purpose of advancing technologies relevant to
the project, effectively separating technology advancement from individual or
commercial intent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;open-design&#34;&gt;Open design:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roadmaps are discussed in the open, and design receives input from all
contributors and maintainers Influence through contribution: organizations and
individuals gain influence over the project through contribution&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ip-cleanliness&#34;&gt;IP Cleanliness:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steps are taken to ensure that all incoming code is legally contributed (DCOs
terms-of-use etc.), that use of approved third party libraries does not create
incompatible dependencies, and that all non-trivial commits have DCOs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;open-licensing&#34;&gt;Open Licensing:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code should be licensed using approved, standard, open-source licenses. (Docker is currently licensed under Apache 2.0)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;7-0-core-criteria&#34;&gt;7.0 Core Criteria&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DGAB will formulate a set of Core Criteria for projects and commercial
products that use the Docker trademarks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Core Criteria will generally cover such areas as: use of standard APIs,
consistent behaviors expected of Docker containers, trademark guidelines,
provenance, upstream contribution models, and alternative distributions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Core Criteria will not be fully defined when the initial DGAB membership is
formulated, it is understood that there is a possibility that certain members
of the initial DGAB may not agree with the Core Criteria when they are fully
defined or may have products/offerings that are not in compliance with the Core
Criteria at the time they are finalized. In this case, the corporate members
will either agree to become compliant within a specified timeframe or else
resign their DGAB position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please help us improve this draft by sending your comments and feedback to
governance@docker.com).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQ for contributors</title>
      <link>https://docs.docker.com/v1.10/opensource/FAQ/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.docker.com/v1.10/opensource/FAQ/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;faq-for-contributors&#34;&gt;FAQ for contributors&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This section contains some frequently asked questions and tips for
troubleshooting problems in your code contribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#how-do-i-set-my-signature:cb7f612e17aad7eb26c06709ef92a867&#34;&gt;How do I set my signature?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#how-do-i-track-changes-from-the-docker-repo-upstream:cb7f612e17aad7eb26c06709ef92a867&#34;&gt;How do I track changes from the docker repo upstream?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#how-do-i-format-my-go-code:cb7f612e17aad7eb26c06709ef92a867&#34;&gt;How do I format my Go code?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-is-the-pre-pull-request-checklist:cb7f612e17aad7eb26c06709ef92a867&#34;&gt;What is the pre-pull request checklist?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#how-should-i-comment-my-code:cb7f612e17aad7eb26c06709ef92a867&#34;&gt;How should I comment my code?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#how-do-i-rebase-my-feature-branch:cb7f612e17aad7eb26c06709ef92a867&#34;&gt;How do I rebase my feature branch?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-i-set-my-signature&#34;&gt;How do I set my signature&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Change to the root of your &lt;code&gt;docker-fork&lt;/code&gt; repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cd docker-fork
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Set your &lt;code&gt;user.name&lt;/code&gt; for the repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git config --local user.name &amp;quot;FirstName LastName&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Set your &lt;code&gt;user.email&lt;/code&gt; for the repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git config --local user.email &amp;quot;emailname@mycompany.com&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-i-track-changes-from-the-docker-repo-upstream&#34;&gt;How do I track changes from the docker repo upstream&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set your local repo to track changes upstream, on the &lt;code&gt;docker&lt;/code&gt; repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Change to the root of your Docker repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cd docker-fork
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add a remote called &lt;code&gt;upstream&lt;/code&gt; that points to &lt;code&gt;docker/docker&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git remote add upstream https://github.com/docker/docker.git
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-i-format-my-go-code&#34;&gt;How do I format my Go code&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;gofmt -s -w filename.go&lt;/code&gt; on each changed file before committing your changes.
Most editors have plug-ins that do the formatting automatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-the-pre-pull-request-checklist&#34;&gt;What is the pre-pull request checklist&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sync and cleanly rebase on top of Docker&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt;; do not mix multiple branches
in the pull request.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Squash your commits into logical units of work using
&lt;code&gt;git rebase -i&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;git push -f&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If your code requires a change to tests or documentation, include code,test,
and documentation changes in the same commit as your code; this ensures a
revert would remove all traces of the feature or fix.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reference each issue in your pull request description (&lt;code&gt;#XXXX&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-should-i-comment-my-code&#34;&gt;How should I comment my code?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Go blog wrote about code comments, it is &lt;a href=&#34;http://goo.gl/fXCRu&#34;
target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;a single page explanation&lt;/a&gt;. A summary follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comments begin with two forward &lt;code&gt;//&lt;/code&gt; slashes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To document a type, variable, constant, function, or even a package, write a
regular comment directly preceding the elements declaration, with no intervening blank
line.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comments on package declarations should provide general package documentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For packages that need large amounts of introductory documentation: the
package comment is placed in its own file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subsequent lines of text are considered part of the same paragraph; you must
leave a blank line to separate paragraphs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Indent pre-formatted text relative to the surrounding comment text (see gob&amp;rsquo;s doc.go for an example).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;URLs are converted to HTML links; no special markup is necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-i-rebase-my-feature-branch&#34;&gt;How do I rebase my feature branch?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always rebase and squash your commits before making a pull request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fetch any of the last minute changes from &lt;code&gt;docker/docker&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git fetch upstream master
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Start an interactive rebase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git rebase -i upstream/master
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rebase opens an editor with a list of commits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    pick 1a79f55 Tweak some of images
    pick 3ce07bb Add a new line
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you run into trouble, &lt;code&gt;git --rebase abort&lt;/code&gt; removes any changes and gets you
back to where you started.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Squash the &lt;code&gt;pick&lt;/code&gt; keyword with &lt;code&gt;squash&lt;/code&gt; on all but the first commit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;pick 1a79f55 Tweak some of images
squash 3ce07bb Add a new line
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After closing the file, &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; opens your editor again to edit the commit
message.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edit and save your commit message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git commit -s
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure your message includes your signature.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Push any changes to your fork on GitHub, using the &lt;code&gt;-f&lt;/code&gt; option to
force the previous change to be overwritten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git push -f origin my-keen-feature
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find an issue</title>
      <link>https://docs.docker.com/v1.10/opensource/kitematic/find_issue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.docker.com/v1.10/opensource/kitematic/find_issue/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;find-an-issue-on-github&#34;&gt;Find an issue on GitHub&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, the Kitematic GUI shows the name of a selected container, but not the ID. The tour shows you how to improve the GUI by adding the container ID to the display items, and integrate the updates into the codebase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To find and claim an issue you want to work on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Go to the &lt;code&gt;docker/kitematic&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/docker/kitematic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Click the &lt;strong&gt;Issues&lt;/strong&gt; link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A list of the open issues appears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../opensource/kitematic/images/list_open_issues.png&#34; alt=&#34;Open issues&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;From the &amp;ldquo;Labels&amp;rdquo; drop-down, select &lt;strong class=&#34;gh-label beginner&#34;&gt;exp/beginner&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system filters to show only open &lt;strong class=&#34;gh-label beginner&#34;&gt;exp/beginner&lt;/strong&gt; issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open an issue that interests you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The comments on the issues describe the problem and can provide information for a potential solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this exercise we will select the issue &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/docker/kitematic/issues/1191&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;#1191 Missing container id&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you find an open issue that both interests you and is unclaimed, add a
&lt;code&gt;#dibs&lt;/code&gt; comment. Make sure that no other user has chosen to work on the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project does not permit external contributors to assign issues to themselves. Read the comments to find if a user claimed the issue by leaving a &lt;code&gt;#dibs&lt;/code&gt; comment on the issue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make a note of the issue number; you will need it for later.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;where-to-go-next&#34;&gt;Where to go next&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to next section to learn &lt;a href=&#34;../v1.10/opensource/kitematic/set_up_dev/&#34;&gt;Set up your Kitematic development environment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(For more about working with open source issues in Docker, see &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.docker.com/opensource/workflow/find-an-issue/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Find an issue&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/docker/docker/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; Docker Contributing Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find and claim an issue</title>
      <link>https://docs.docker.com/v1.10/opensource/workflow/find-an-issue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.docker.com/v1.10/opensource/workflow/find-an-issue/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;!-- 
note: don&#39;t use blank lines inside the style-block;
hugo converts them to paragraphs, causing the styles to be ignored
--&gt;

&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
.gh-label {
    display: inline-block;
    padding: 3px 4px;
    font-size: 12px;
    font-weight: bold;
    line-height: 1;
    color: #fff;
    border-radius: 2px;
}
.gh-label.beginner { background-color: #A8DBA8; color: #333333; }
.gh-label.intermediate { background-color: #79BD9A; color: #333333; }
.gh-label.expert { background-color: #3B8686; color: #ffffff; }
.gh-label.kinddocs { background-color: #A8E6CE; color: #333333; }
.gh-label.kindbug { background-color: #FF8C94; color: #333333; }
.gh-label.enhancement { background-color: #E8CAAF; color: #333333; }
.gh-label.content { background-color: #CDD3C2; color: #333333; }
.gh-label.kindfeature { background-color: #AAB3AB; color: #333333; }
.gh-label.graphics { background-color: #E1EFCB; color: #333333; }
.gh-label.improvement { background-color: #EBD2BB; color: #333333; }
.gh-label.proposal { background-color: #FFD9C0; color: #333333; }
.gh-label.kindquestion { background-color: #EBEFC9; color: #333333; }
.gh-label.usecase { background-color: #F0E4C2; color: #333333; }
.gh-label.kinddocs { background-color: #B5E9D5; color: #333333; }
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;find-and-claim-an-issue&#34;&gt;Find and claim an issue&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a contributor, you can work on any open issue you want. You can view
issues in the Issues tab in every repository. If you are new to
contributing, use the filter option to find suitable issues. You can
filter issues by Author, Labels, Milestones, and Assignee or sort by
time such as newest and oldest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;understand-the-issue-types&#34;&gt;Understand the issue types&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help you identify the different types of issues, our maintainers
assign labels to issues. Labels are color-coded and help you categorize
and filter issues. There are four labels categories; kind, area,
experience, and priority. You can filter using one or more labels. The
kind and experience labels are useful for new contributors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following table describes the kind labels.
&lt;strong class=&#34;foobar&#34;&gt;kind/bug&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Kind Label&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong class=&#34;foobar gh-label kindbug&#34;&gt;kind/bug&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
          These issues contain bugs. The cause may or may not be known
          at triage time so debugging should be taken account into the
          time estimate.
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong class=&#34;gh-label kinddocs&#34;&gt;kind/docs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
          These issues contain documentation, man pages, articles,
          blogs, or other significant word-driven task.
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong class=&#34;gh-label enhancement&#34;&gt;kind/enhancement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
          These issues contain enhancements that are not bugs or new
          features but can improve usability or performance of
          a project component.
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong class=&#34;gh-label kindfeature&#34;&gt;kind/feature&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
          These issues contain new features, functionality, and
          elements that the project does not currently support.
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong class=&#34;gh-label kindquestion&#34;&gt;kind/question&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
          These issues contain a user or contributor question that
          requires a response.
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following table describes the experience level guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Exp Label&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong class=&#34;gh-label beginner&#34;&gt;exp/beginner&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
          You are new to Docker and Golang and want to start
          contributing to the project. These issues are for beginners who
          want to learn the basics. We encourage new contributors to start
          with exp/beginner issues.
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong class=&#34;gh-label intermediate&#34;&gt;exp/intermediate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
          You understand the core concepts of Docker and are
          comfortable with Golang. These issues are for intermediates who
          want to dive deeper into the project.
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong class=&#34;gh-label expert&#34;&gt;exp/expert&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
          You are proficient with Docker and Golang and are actively
          involved in the community. These issues are for experts who
          understand the rationale behind design decisions and where the
          project is headed.
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As stated, these labels are guidelines. You might have written a whole
plugin for Docker in a personal project and never contributed to
Docker. With that kind of experience, you could take on an &lt;strong
class=&#34;gh-label expert&#34;&gt;exp/expert&lt;/strong&gt; issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;claim-a-beginner-issue&#34;&gt;Claim a beginner issue&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To claim an issue:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Go to the &lt;code&gt;docker/docker&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a
href=&#34;https://github.com/docker/docker&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Click the &amp;ldquo;Issues&amp;rdquo; tab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A list of the open issues appears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../opensource/workflow/images/issue_list.png&#34; alt=&#34;Open issues&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;From the &amp;ldquo;Labels&amp;rdquo; drop-down, select &lt;strong class=&#34;gh-label beginner&#34;&gt;exp/beginner&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system filters to show only open &lt;strong class=&#34;gh-label beginner&#34;&gt;exp/beginner&lt;/strong&gt; issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open an issue that interests you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The comments on the issues describe the problem and can provide information for a potential
solution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you find an open issue that both interests you and is unclaimed, add a
&lt;code&gt;#dibs&lt;/code&gt; comment. Make sure that no other user has chosen to work on the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project does not permit external contributors to assign issues to themselves. Read
the comments to find if a user claimed the issue by leaving a
&lt;code&gt;#dibs&lt;/code&gt; comment on the issue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your issue # will be different depending on what you claimed. After a moment, Gordon the Docker
bot, changes the issue status to claimed. The following example shows issue #11038.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../opensource/workflow/images/easy_issue.png&#34; alt=&#34;Easy issue&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make a note of the issue number; you will need it for later.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sync-your-fork-and-create-a-new-branch&#34;&gt;Sync your fork and create a new branch&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have followed along in this guide, you forked the &lt;code&gt;docker/docker&lt;/code&gt;
repository. Maybe that was an hour ago or a few days ago. In any case, before
you start working on your issue, sync your repository with the upstream
&lt;code&gt;docker/docker&lt;/code&gt; master. Syncing ensures your repository has the latest
changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To sync your repository:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open a terminal on your local host.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Change directory to the &lt;code&gt;docker-fork&lt;/code&gt; root.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cd ~/repos/docker-fork
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Checkout the master branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git checkout master
Switched to branch &#39;master&#39;
Your branch is up-to-date with &#39;origin/master&#39;.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recall that &lt;code&gt;origin/master&lt;/code&gt; is a branch on your remote GitHub repository.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make sure you have the upstream remote &lt;code&gt;docker/docker&lt;/code&gt; by listing them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git remote -v
origin  https://github.com/moxiegirl/docker.git (fetch)
origin  https://github.com/moxiegirl/docker.git (push)
upstream    https://github.com/docker/docker.git (fetch)
upstream    https://github.com/docker/docker.git (push)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the &lt;code&gt;upstream&lt;/code&gt; is missing, add it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git remote add upstream https://github.com/docker/docker.git
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fetch all the changes from the &lt;code&gt;upstream master&lt;/code&gt; branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git fetch upstream master
remote: Counting objects: 141, done.
remote: Compressing objects: 100% (29/29), done.
remote: Total 141 (delta 52), reused 46 (delta 46), pack-reused 66
Receiving objects: 100% (141/141), 112.43 KiB | 0 bytes/s, done.
Resolving deltas: 100% (79/79), done.
From github.com:docker/docker
 * branch            master     -&amp;gt; FETCH_HEAD
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This command says get all the changes from the &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch belonging to
the &lt;code&gt;upstream&lt;/code&gt; remote.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rebase your local master with the &lt;code&gt;upstream/master&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git rebase upstream/master
First, rewinding head to replay your work on top of it...
Fast-forwarded master to upstream/master.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This command applies all the commits from the upstream master to your local
master.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Check the status of your local branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git status
On branch master
Your branch is ahead of &#39;origin/master&#39; by 38 commits.
  (use &amp;quot;git push&amp;quot; to publish your local commits)
nothing to commit, working directory clean
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your local repository now has all the changes from the &lt;code&gt;upstream&lt;/code&gt; remote. You
need to push the changes to your own remote fork which is &lt;code&gt;origin master&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Push the rebased master to &lt;code&gt;origin master&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git push origin master
Username for &#39;https://github.com&#39;: moxiegirl
Password for &#39;https://moxiegirl@github.com&#39;:
Counting objects: 223, done.
Compressing objects: 100% (38/38), done.
Writing objects: 100% (69/69), 8.76 KiB | 0 bytes/s, done.
Total 69 (delta 53), reused 47 (delta 31)
To https://github.com/moxiegirl/docker.git
   8e107a9..5035fa1  master -&amp;gt; master
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create a new feature branch to work on your issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your branch name should have the format &lt;code&gt;XXXX-descriptive&lt;/code&gt; where &lt;code&gt;XXXX&lt;/code&gt; is
the issue number you are working on. For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git checkout -b 11038-fix-rhel-link
Switched to a new branch &#39;11038-fix-rhel-link&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your branch should be up-to-date with the &lt;code&gt;upstream/master&lt;/code&gt;. Why? Because you
branched off a freshly synced master.  Let&amp;rsquo;s check this anyway in the next
step.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rebase your branch from upstream/master.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git rebase upstream/master
Current branch 11038-fix-rhel-link is up to date.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, your local branch, your remote repository, and the Docker
repository all have identical code. You are ready to make changes for your
issue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;where-to-go-next&#34;&gt;Where to go next&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, you know what you want to work on and you have a branch to do
your work in.  Go onto the next section to learn &lt;a href=&#34;../v1.10/opensource/workflow/work-issue/&#34;&gt;how to work on your
changes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get started</title>
      <link>https://docs.docker.com/v1.10/opensource/kitematic/get_started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.docker.com/v1.10/opensource/kitematic/get_started/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;contribute-to-kitematic&#34;&gt;Contribute to Kitematic&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kitematic is an open source project that simplifies the Docker experience. It
automates Docker installation and setup, and provides an interactive graphical
user interface (GUI) for working with containers. You can use Kitematic to create, run, and manage Docker containers, and find public images on Docker Hub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../opensource/kitematic/images/gui-splash-hub.png&#34; alt=&#34;Kitematic GUI&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.docker.com/kitematic/userguide&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; Kitematic user guide&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about it from a user perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-welcome-your-contributions&#34;&gt;We welcome your contributions!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;d like to see Kitematic evolve
with community contributed add-ons, extensions, themes, plug-ins, and cool, new
features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;start-the-developer-tour&#34;&gt;Start the developer tour&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re new to working with Docker open source projects or new to
the Kitematic codebase, this quick tour will help you get started. Follow along with these steps to set up your Kitematic development environment and practice working on an example issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../v1.10/opensource/kitematic/find_issue/&#34;&gt;Find a Kitematic issue on GitHub and fork&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../v1.10/opensource/kitematic/set_up_dev/&#34;&gt;Set up your Kitematic development environment and clone the repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../v1.10/opensource/kitematic/work_issue/&#34;&gt;Develop in Kitematic (work on an issue)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../v1.10/opensource/kitematic/create_pr/&#34;&gt;Review your branch and create a pull request (PR)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../v1.10/opensource/kitematic/next_steps/&#34;&gt;Where to learn more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;where-to-go-next&#34;&gt;Where to go next&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../v1.10/opensource/kitematic/find_issue/&#34;&gt;Find an issue on GitHub&lt;/a&gt; to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>